Go Cowboys.
Cowboys win. Let's go. There's still
work to be done. My legacy I want to lay
it on the world for
The heartbeat of this football team is
different. I will fight WITH YOU GUYS
ANYTIME, ANY PLACE.
>> [music]
>> We can only do so much alone, but
together we're a hell of a group.
We're building a monster.
Can August and training camp just come
quicker? Can it be here already? That
wants to make us run through a wall as
Brian Schottenheimer, Dak Prescott, and
the Cowboys team prepare for 2026.
[music]
Welcome in to Cowboys Spotlight from the
Globe Life Studios at the Star in Frisco
alongside Nicole Hutchison and Mickey
Spagnola. I'm Kyle Youmans. It is a busy
time of year for Dallas. Free agency and
of course the trade market are open for
business and the Cowboys have been very
busy trying to work their way back to
relevancy on the defensive side of the
ball. Reporter from The Athletic John
Machota was very detailed in what moves
the Cowboys have made on that side of
the ball specifically, but I want to ask
you guys, what has been the most
specific move or the most significant
move that we've seen so far, Nicole?
>> I'm going safety and I'm going Jaylen
Thompson. You talk about the most
pivotal issues that the Cowboys had in
that secondary last year. They were the
worst passing defense in the NFL in
2025. Too many explosive plays, too many
missed angles. I mean, you name it, they
had it. Jaylen Thompson immediately
fixes that. You talk about a guy who had
a missed tackle rate no higher than 6%
since 2021. He brings you versatility.
He's of course worked and played along
the defensive back defensive backfield,
every position. But he also brings those
instincts, the processing speed that
Christian Parker wants. Against the
Bears, Reese Justin Fields breaks from
his assignment, interception in the end
zone last year. He had They see that
Trevor Lawrence is going play action. He
blitzes off the edge and of course gets
the uh strip sack there. So, you talk
about a guy who brings so much to this
defense. He changes a lot of things and
I think he will. Cal.
>> Mickey, well, I am going with a
cornerback. If they're having trouble
uh
covering the passes, I need a corner out
there. And I need a corner [music] that
has more than 20 starts in the NFL. So,
I'm going with Kobe Durant. Uh he's got
39 NFL starts. The only guy on this team
also that has more than 20 NFL starts is
Jourdan Lewis. So, they needed some
experience at corner. Uh Kobe Durant uh
has been a starter in the league.
Uh they only signed him to a one-year
five uh up to five and a half million,
but here's the key thing. He had three
interceptions last year
uh in the regular season and three
interceptions in the playoffs. They need
a guy other than Jourdan Lew- Lewis at
cornerback [music] that has some
experience. So, I think he was uh an
absolute necessity. Yeah, he was a top
100 NFL free agent according to nfl.com.
Now, Mickey, real quickly here, what's a
position they still need to address?
Middle linebacker, middle linebacker,
middle linebacker, right? Absolutely and
they need some experience there. So,
either in the draft uh a late free agent
signing or they got to make a trade. I'm
going defensive end. They need another
pass rusher. We don't know what this
real 3-4 base will look like, but you
need some more big bodies up there that
can control gaps and hold up double
teams. Yeah, and if you can add both of
those things and then you add Rashaan
Gary, you add Jaylen Thompson on the
back end, and then your top two draft
picks as well, might be pretty good
going into the year on the defensive
side of the ball. With more on these
additions and let's break down the film
with Anthony Dorsett, former safety and
cornerback in the NFL.
Typically what you hear guys talk about
safeties and you always lose something
in coverage a lot of times. But let's
highlight him one more time. Find out
where he is again. He's also not in the
box again. Where he at? He's right down
here and he's getting ready to be in
coverage, all right? Now, he's not
covering the tight end. He's actually in
coverage on the receiver here. So, what
he has, if you'll allow me to get to
that,
is this. He's man-to-man right here.
This guy's man-to-man and you see man
all [music] the way across the board,
all right? Now, snap of the ball, he's
supposed to stay where? Hip to man on
this guy right here. He actually gets
beat a little bit if you look at it,
okay? And if you if he's winning in this
position, he's actually here. He's
upfield, all [music] right? But he's
actually behind the guy. Now, no panic
at all with his back to the ball. First
of all, he's comfortable in coverage.
Now, when he finally does catch up, he
gets right back to the hip, plays
through the hands, and [music] knocks
the ball out, makes the pass break up in
the end zone. All right? Awesome play
for a safety.
>> What are Cowboys fans going to see
differently now that they have a guy
like Rashaan Gary at their disposal plus
in a 3-4 front compared to maybe a 4-3?
First off, you're going to notice the
everybody's going to be a lot bigger on
defense in the front seven. Your outside
linebackers are going to look like
D-linemen. Your D-linemen are going to
look like nose tackles and everybody's
going to be a lot bigger. But everybody
has a different responsibility too as
well. When you have the 3-4 that they're
going to be running now, guys have to be
two-gap guys. So, this guy's going to be
going here, he's going to be going
there. This guy has there, that guy has
there. This guy's going to be trying to
come in here, going out there as well.
And they have to be strong [music] at
the point of attack. Now, where are we
going to find Gary at?
He's right over here right now, all
right? The pass rush specialist. He's on
the edge in the wide nine. Now, what
they're typically going to do is they
have two guys out here that can
potentially block him. You got the
tackle here, you got the tight end here,
all right? Now, what they're going to do
is snap of the ball, they're both going
to try to engage him. Now, Gary has to
get from there, of course,
all the way back here to the
quarterback. [music] Now, if you let the
play snap, you're going to see Ertz
right here,
tight end, he's trying to trying to
engage him. He gets rid of the tight end
right now. Same thing he has to go
through to to the tackle now. The tackle
is trying to set back [music] here to
make sure he cuts off that angle, but
watch how Gary uses his speed and power,
all right? And he has [music] vision of
the quarterback still to get back here
and watch what he does to dip and rip
and get under, uses leverage, boom. Sack
in the end sack I'm sorry, sack in the
backfield. Jayden Daniels is one of the
most dangerous quarterbacks out there to
get. So, they they to keep him in the
pocket, that was an awesome play right
there.
And when we come back here on Cowboys
Spotlight, we're going to hear from some
of the newest [music] Dallas Cowboys as
they sign the contract to become a part
of America's Team.
The Dallas Cowboys Spotlight is
presented by AT&T, an official sponsor
of the Dallas Cowboys, and by the Texas
Lottery. Play the games of Texas with
the Texas Lottery. Play today.
It's a crowded defensive tackle room
with a ton of talent. [music] You got
Quinnen Williams, you got Kenny Clark,
and now you've got Otito Obgonnia, new
signee of the free agent variety here
for the Dallas Cowboys. And Otito,
welcome back to Texas. Houston born and
raised, but what's it like to now be a
part of the Dallas Cowboys? Uh it's a
dream come true. I mean, I've been
following the Cowboys for for as long as
I know being a Houston native.
>> [music]
>> Um
it's it's a special place in my heart.
Always wanted to play for this team.
Um so, it's a really big deal for me. If
you were to give your scouting report,
your own self-scout out to Cowboys fans
out there, what are the Cowboys fans
going to get to see from Otito Obgonnia
this year? Yeah, you're going to see a
dominant run game, dominant at the point
of attack, um stuff in the run,
um A-gap to A-gap to D-gap. Um you're
going to feel you're going to see that
you're going to feel it feel the
presence, um stop the run for sure.
Well, the Cowboys were looking to add
another dog to that cornerback room and
they did so with Kobe Durant on a
one-year deal. Talk about, you know,
what this Dallas defense is getting from
you.
Um they're getting a a guy that the
media says is too small, but you know,
it ain't all about the size and the dog
is the size and the heart of the dog.
So, you know, the land shark coming to
make plays and add on to this defense.
Just create takeaways and get the ball
back to Dak.
Uh let Dak do what he do. Um you know,
I'm excited for it.
Like I said, uh
got great guys in that secondary and I'm
just, you know, here to add on.
Ladies and gentlemen, this is Patrick
Nosey Walker. I am standing here with
the newest Cowboys safety, P.J. Locke.
And P.J., we're going to get right into
it. Native of Beaumont, South Texas. You
went to the University [music] of Texas.
How does it feel to be home?
Man, it's such a surreal moment.
>> [music]
>> Full circle moment. I said, my my wife
is from Fort Worth.
My whole family grew up Cowboys fans
and, you [music] know, to be right here
able to play for the home team, man,
it's it's such a blessing. It's a
miracle. One thing is you probably guys
probably don't know, but I played with
Overshown in college.
>> [music]
>> So, he can go. And he was playing he was
playing safety at the time. So,
But yeah, man, I think I think we have a
good team. It starts with having the big
guys ready. And we have a good O-line.
All we need is a All we need is a good
D-line and we we got that. So, [music]
we got the hardest part done. Now, it's
just like getting the scheme together,
getting everybody on the same page with
that. And [music] you know, DBs making
making plays in the back end. And
also starts with communication. [music]
And CP is the right coach for that
because he's he's very very detailed.
Talk about the connections, of course,
reuniting with BT Jordan, one of the
premier pass rush specialist here. Also
coach CP, who's now the defensive
coordinator, who was on the staff in
Green Bay. But I know your closest
friend Kenny Clark, who you created a
havoc up front in the trenches in Green
Bay. Just how much are you looking
forward to playing alongside him as
well? Yeah, this just this whole you
know, experience. I'm just everything
you know, the Cowboys organization is
putting together. I'm happy to be a part
of them. Happy to be you know, to start
up some change you know, in the right
way. And you know, the guys that you
named, especially [music] being able to
come back, you know, play with a guy
that I know and just his work ethic and
what he means and what the the game
football means to KC. Means the same to
me. So I just can't wait to go to work
and show the Cowboys nation what I'm all
about.
Free agency rolling on here now with one
of the Dallas Cowboys latest signees,
quarterback Sam Howell. Sam, thanks for
the time.
I know it's been a whirlwind past couple
of days for you, but you're signed now
here in Dallas. What's this experience
been like for you so far? Uh yeah, it's
been great. Um [music] you know, getting
in the building and meeting everybody.
Um it's been been really cool. Um you
know, Dallas was my team growing up. So
it's it's a dream come true to you know,
be here and be a Dallas Cowboy. In this
quarterback room, four of you now. I
know it's going to be a long process
from now [music]
towards the season. What's your mindset
when it comes to competition and being
able to set yourself out from the rest
of the pack? Yeah, I just try to be the
best version of myself. You know, I just
try to put my head down and go to work
every single day and um you know, try
not to worry too much about what the
what the result or the outcomes are. I
just try to do everything I can and be
the best version of myself every day and
you know, kind of let the results take
care of themselves.
Well, the Cowboys have bolstered up
[music] their safety room adding Jaylen
Thompson, former safety for the Arizona
Cardinals. Welcome to the Dallas
Cowboys. [music] How you feeling? What's
this last what, 36 hours been like for
you? Uh it's been amazing. Blessed. Uh
just an amazing opportunity to play for
America's team. So this is uh
once-in-a-lifetime type opportunity. I'm
ready to get it going. What are some of
the things that you know, the Cowboys
fans can expect? What type of safety can
they expect to see out of you? Uh
physical safety, a safety that can do
pretty much everything. Um I don't
consider myself just a safety, a DB in
general. Nickel, corner, [music]
um free safety, strong safety, wherever
they need me at. Um that's where I'm
playing.
Now that we've met some of the newest
faces for the Dallas Cowboys, what's new
in the world of the NFL? We check in
with Tommy Yarish from the NFL owners
meetings next.
>> [music]
>> The Dallas Cowboys Spotlight was
presented by AT&T, an official sponsor
of the Dallas Cowboys. And by the Texas
Lottery. Play the games of Texas with
the Texas Lottery. Play today.
Oh, yes, the 2026 NFL Draft is nearing.
>> [music]
>> And the Cowboys have eight overall
selections including two in the first
round. But here's the kicker, they don't
pick again from pick 20 until pick 92 in
the third round. They got to get those
first two round picks right. Back here
on Cowboys Spotlight wrapping things up
from the Global Life Studios at The Star
in Frisco with Nicole Hutchison and with
Mickey Spagnola. I'm Kyle Youmans.
Mickey, I'm going to let you kick things
off with our mock drafts. Still a month
out from the NFL Draft, but what are you
looking forward to the most for the
Cowboys?
>> So this is my mock draft and I can
manipulate it any way I want. So I'm
manipulating for the guy that's probably
a pipe dream. Defensive end from Miami,
Ruben Bain Jr. Saw this guy play early
in the season. I didn't know if he was
for real. Asked Cowboys VP of personnel
uh Will McClay, is this guy that good?
He goes, he'll never get to us. Well, in
my mock, he gets [music] to us. And then
at number 20, I got uh
Anthony Hill Jr. I think the Cowboys
trade down. I looked at some other mocks
and after the 20th pick, it was a bunch
of positions the Cowboys [music] aren't
interested in. So go get another day two
pick.
>> I like it. Mickey's [music] pick. He was
able to manipulate it the way he wants.
Nicole, what's yours? I was stressed out
doing this mock draft, okay? Because I
was going in my head like Caleb Downs,
Sunny Styles, 12. No, it's not going to
happen. I don't think it's going to be
realistic. So I have Jermaine Burton,
cornerback out of Tennessee at pick
number 12. I think that he matches the
temperament that this Cowboys defense
wants in terms of
taking the ball away. He had four
interceptions, 13 passes defended in
2024. Of course, he tore his ACL, didn't
play the 2025 season. So I think also
his pro day kind of shined a light on
what he can possibly do. But you talk
about at pick number 20, I had Dylan
Feeneyman, the safety out of Oregon. I
think he's a smart, [music] athletic
safety. He can do pretty much
everything. So I'm going to keep it at
that. I tried to be realistic. Like I
said, Kyle, it stressed me the hell out.
>> [laughter]
>> I like it there. I think it's fun to see
Mickey go
uh front seven and then for you to go
all secondary in your mock draft. So a
couple things to look forward to there.
Jermaine Burton would be the number one
safety on the board there since at
number nine, Kansas City takes Mansour
Delane. All right, here's my mock draft.
First pick all the way through 20, I
think it's going to be Mansour Delane.
I'm also optimistic in this case. He's
my number one corner on the board. I
think he's going to be there for Dallas
at 12, especially if some of those
offensive tackles start to maneuver
their way into the early parts of the
top 10. That's what you're rooting for
if you're Dallas. You want every
offensive player possible to go in front
of them at 12 just to push those better
defensive players down the board. And
then at 20, you need a middle
linebacker. As Mickey said early in the
show, you're going to get one that can
wear the green dot as a rookie. CJ
Allen, who called the defense for
Georgia during his time in college out
in Athens. I think he's an instinctual
player. He's an athletic player. He's
still got a little bit to go in terms of
the speed and the size elements, but I
really like what we see from CJ Allen. I
think if you get both of these guys,
Cowboys fans should be doing cartwheels
cuz you get two immediate starters in
the NFL Draft with those first two round
picks. Now, here's the thing. You can
listen to every single pick along the
way from the draft show coming up on
draft weekend. We kick things off early
on night one and we go wall to wall
every single pick available on Dallas
Cowboys.com and streaming on the Cowboys
YouTube channel at certain times
throughout draft weekend. Be sure to
join us all draft weekend long as we'll
hear the next group of [music] Cowboys
hear their name called on stage. That
does it for us on Cowboys Spotlight.